Uzair Rahim

12640 Picket Rope LN Austin, TX 78727 512-203-5836 | www.uzairrahim.com | uzairrahim@gmail.com | linkedin/uzairrahim

About

I specialize in designing user flows, user interfaces, and front-end web development using HTML/CSS and JavaScript. I have been developing my skills for over ten years to get the job done quickly and effectively.

Responsive application design is my newfound love and I enjoy designing and developing web and mobile apps for all platforms, devices, and screen sizes.

In my free time I enjoy photography and playing Cricket.

Skills

My skills include, but are not limited to:

- HTML
 - o Responsive Layout
- CSS
 - Media Queries
- JavaScript
 - jQuery
 - Underscore.js
 - o Backbone.js
 - Handelbars.js
 - o Require.js
 - o Node.js
 - Socket.io
 - o Bower.js
 - o Gulp.js
 - o React.js

- o Grunt.js
- o Angular.js
- Facebook API
- Twitter API
- Usability Testing
- Database
 - o SQL
 - MySQL
 - o PL/SQL
- Design
 - User Interface
 - o User Experience
 - Mobile Apps
 - Photoshop
 - Balsamiq

- Java
- Git
- ActionScript
- Xcode
- Flash
- 3D Studio Max
- PHP
- JSP

Experience

Software Engineer

HotSchedules Inc.

Responsible for developing Web Applications; collaborate with server side developers to implement RESTful services. Incorporate new emerging libraries like Require.js, Grunt.js etc. to optimize and improve client side code.

Aug 2013 - Present

UX/UI Designer

HotSchedules Inc.

Responsible for designing and developing user interfaces and user flows for existing and new web and mobile applications; developing functional prototype for testing and presentations; produce assets and scripts for development team; liaison between development team and user experience design team.

HotSchedules iOS app ranked #2 in the app store under the business category soon after its launch.

Oct 2011 - Aug 2013

Usability Engineer

360training.com

Design and develop user-centered designs for enterprise applications. Improve the usability, usefulness and desirability of the applications. Responsible for look-and-feel and information flow; develop functioning prototypes for usability testing and presentations.

Oct 2008 - Oct 2011

Sr./ Multimedia Developer

360training.com

Responsible for designing and developing online and CD based elearning courses, layout designs including objectives of the courses, navigational and user interfaces using Adobe Flash and ActionScript; design company intros including products and services; design and develop interactive activities for e-learning courses. Supervise production of e-learning courses manage a team of designers; participate in product roadmap development; project management and timely completion of tasks.

Jun 2004 - Oct 2008

Education

Texas State University

Bachelor of Applied Arts & Science (B.A.A.S)

Program Translators – Data Structure – Computer Architecture – Digital Logic – Database Systems – Software Engineer – Theory of Automata – Object Oriented Design and Implementation – Technical Writing 2010-2015

Austin Community College

<u>Associates of Applied Science (A.A.S)</u>
Solid understanding of Software Engineering, Object Oriented Design and Implementation, Data Structures and Digital Logic

2007 - 2010